AMARNATH JAMALE

Platform Engineer (Azure, DevOps, Unix)

A computer geek with professional experience of 4 years as Platform Engineer. Skilled in Technologies related to Infrastructures like Cloud, DevOps, Unix, Container Orchestrations and Automation. Proficiently working in Agile environment with strong analytical and problem-solving skills backed by versatile skillsets and impeccable written and verbal communication skills.

CONTACT



+47 455 28 455





amar@jamale.org



Økernveien 5B, 0653 Oslo



in/amarnathjamale/



github.com/amarnathjamale



amar.jamale.org (Portfolio)

PROFESSIONAL EXPERIENCE

Tata Consultancy Services Limited, February 2019 - Present

Azure DevOps Engineer, May 2021 - Present

- Developed multiple Azure Pipelines using Azure DevOps to have a CICD deployment for several applications with laaC
- Leveraged Biceps for CICD for application and platform deployments
- Migrated OnPrem workloads to Azure with standardized pipelines
- Provided Azure Administrator support for Cloud Workloads

DevOps Engineer, December 2019 - Present

- Developed several Ansible playbooks to automate daily activities, including system configuration backups, OS patching, and application installations, saving \$3.5 million USD annually.
- Deployed the Ansible playbook for automating the post Azure migration tasks saving the operation team's 4 hours per migrated server
- Designed, deployed, and maintained a scalable and efficient container platform using Kubernetes and Docker for running various applications.
- Developed and implemented Ansible automations for container deployment, scaling and management operational processes.
- Built numerous Podman images for ansible execution environments.
- Implemented multiple bash/python/perl scripts to streamline complex and timeconsuming tasks such as cluster monitoring, LDAP access mirroring, and IDM access standardizing, saving 300 hours of work per month.
- Fully automated Linux Patching with addons like compliance reporting, ITSM management and application start/stop/validation resulted in highest uptime.
- Deployed a website using jQuery JavaScript that updates periodically using an ansible playbook that validates environment. It also provides a platform for handover, decommission, ilom monitoring, Infra capacity, etc. reports generated
- Rearchitected OS Hardening using Dynamic Ansible playbook generation based on the OpenSCAP profile enabling to control and provision the perfect hardened Infrastructure for application teams.
- Carried out POC for Event Driven Ansible. Deployed EDA solution for internal projects like infrastructure monitoring, GitOps for playbook linting, etc.
- Created and deployed systemd services/cronjobs to automate application start/stop at boot removing dependency of application team in many activities paving the pathway towards many automations.
- Implemented Dynamic Config as Code practice for infrastructure management.

Unix Engineer, February 2019 - Present

- Delivered projects involving OS building on both VMware and physical hardware with cluster systems such as PCS, VCS, and SunOS from Satellite.
- User and Access management by OpenLDAP, OUD & RedHat IDM
- Provided operational and development support on across Unix Platform.
- Created and maintained a ServiceNow Kanban Dashboard for increasing work effectiveness of my team and avoid any SLA breaches.
- Recorded a series of comprehensive knowledge transfer sessions for new team members, aimed at organization's processes and infrastructure.

SKILLS

Platforms: Cloud: Azure, AWS, GCP RedHat: RHEL, Ansible Automation Platform/Tower and Hub, OpenShift, Satellite, IDM, Insights
Oracle: Solaris, LDAP, OpsCenter, OUD

DevOps: Ansible, Docker, Git, Azure, Kubernetes, Jenkins, Terraform, Bash, Python, PowerShell, Azure DevOps, VMware, Splunk, Jira, Confluence,

Bitbucket,

ServiceNow,

Dynatrace, Nimsoft

GitLab,

Sides: HTML, CSS, JavaScript, jQuery, ReactJS, Machine Learning, Perl, Ethical Hacking, Android OS Development

CERTIFICATIONS

Azure DevOps Expert /AZ-400
Azure Developer Associate /AZ-204
Azure Administrator Associate /AZ-104
Azure Fundamentals / AZ-900

AWARDS

- ✓ Beyond Excellence Award
- ✓ Best Team Award x2
- ✓ Most Valuable Team Member x3
- ✓ Star of the Month Award x2
- ✓ Maitree Prize Award
- ✓ On the Spot Award x2

EDUCATION





